David Mendenhall: Hello?
Gary Young: Hey.
David Mendenhall: Hey.
Gary Young: Jarek says they're having lots of excitement with, regulatory investigations.
David Mendenhall: Jarek?
Gary Young: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: It'll be fine.
David Mendenhall: Right.
Gary Young: Did anybody fired in the last 2 days?
Gary Young: Me? No?
David Mendenhall: Wade.
David Mendenhall: That was the… that's what we talked about last time.
David Mendenhall: That he had gotten his coworker fired.
Wade: I didn't get him fired, he got himself.
David Mendenhall: himself fired, see?
Wade: Anyway, he's not officially fired, he's still on payroll, but he's doing nothing.
David Mendenhall: Sounds like he won.
Wade: I mean, I wouldn't say he's… yeah, he's….
Gary Young: He said.
Wade: He's still wasting time, he's just not wasting my time.
Wade: No, his replacement, or, you know, the guy who's picked up the slack has been just amazing, like, since, you know, since he took over, ….
Gary Young: A week, week.
Wade: We've got our….
Gary Young: The root complex completely, buttoned up.
Wade: That's all working, and now we're…
Wade: Halfway to getting our USB endpoint working, and …
Wade: Probably be close to getting Ethernet next week, and then we'll be done.
Wade: Are you in a closet?
Gary Young: I mean, that just sounds like a virtual background, right?
Gary Young: Sweet.
Wade: He is, isn't he?
Gary Young: What entertaining virtual backgrounds can we make up here?
Wade: I don't know, what's wrong with the virtual dog in the background?
David Mendenhall: It's not like Gary's room is all that attractive, you know?
Wade: Mine's not, and I….
David Mendenhall: Yours is… well, you have a dog, at least. It's a little bit more interesting in the background. Gary has cat, just not in frame.
Wade: But you're, like, surrounded by hanging clothes, like, it's a closet, isn't it?
David Mendenhall: It is a closet.
Wade: It's like a very nice, spacious walk-in closet.
David Mendenhall: the walk-in closet.
Wade: I mean, what's the… isn't Grostatis? Like, isn't it in a garage or something? It sure looks like it.
David Mendenhall: Garage, yeah.
Gary Young: Cruzzy.
Wade: Not in a garage.
David Mendenhall: Excuse me.
Wade: Might be very short.
Wade: Let's see….
David Mendenhall: He'll be here.
Wade: I know, he got, ….
David Mendenhall: It's gonna be a short session, though.
Wade: Well, we'll just end at 10.30 like always, right?
David Mendenhall: Marius.
Wade: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh.
David Mendenhall: Alright, we're all here, let's do it! GM.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
Wade: Hello, hello?
Kostadis Roussos: Old.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: Can you not hear us?
David Mendenhall: Nick is so little in that picture, Casados.
Kostadis Roussos: I know.
Kostadis Roussos: I just… Yeah, it was a long time ago.
Kostadis Roussos: I, just, fixed my audio.
Kostadis Roussos: Huh, can you guys see me?
Wade: Yeah, we can see you.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
Wade: David refuses to come out of the closet.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Which one of many?
Wade: The one he's in.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm feeling awkward here, right? Like, that this is some kind of private conversation.
David Mendenhall: Wade is amused that my computer is set up in a closet, because I live in a tiny little house.
David Mendenhall: Where there's no space.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, really?
Wade: I mean, I, … my desk is actually embedded in the closet in this room, so we gutted it, …
Wade: And, like, the desk takes up the entire, like, width of the closet. It's really nice.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: So, that's cool.
Kostadis Roussos: But, like, my favorite, … Flex is one of my coworkers at VMware.
Kostadis Roussos: Matt Amder, you may recall him, Dave. He had… he sat in a hallway between his laundry over here and his bedroom over here, and there was a tiny little window.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So we're talking about a distance that's…
Kostadis Roussos: you know, how much of a hallway it is, right? And so what he did was he put a fake bookshelf
Kostadis Roussos: Right above the window.
Wade: Oh, like a… like just a matte painting or something?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, just, you know, one of those tiny little bookshelves, it was, like, maybe… I think….
Wade: Like a decorative shelf. Like a dollhouse bookshelf?
David Mendenhall: You probably, if you put more than two books on it, it would….
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Like, something really cheap, but it made it look like he was in a real office.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
David Mendenhall: Well done. He didn't have, … he didn't have his shirts hanging up in the background. That's good, good for him.
Kostadis Roussos: I just used the zoom blur feature, but….
David Mendenhall: I had to turn it off earlier tonight because…
David Mendenhall: Yes. Victor and I were doing a joint Zoom, and with Blur on, He was blurred out.
David Mendenhall: So….
Kostadis Roussos: Really?
David Mendenhall: I forgot to turn it.
David Mendenhall: on again.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so… we're marching back to Phandalin, I believe.
Wade: We're going to Leilan, right?
Wade: Hi, buddy.
David Mendenhall: We can… we can rest in Phandalin. I've got some business there, I gotta….
Kostadis Roussos: Well, okay, guys, you're not supposed to go to Phandalin, the Leilan now.
David Mendenhall: … well, we'll talk about that, but that's okay.
Gary Young: Act 3. We're still in Act 1.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: I like speedrunning.
Wade: We kill our drought, we put her in a box, we throw fire on the ground.
Kostadis Roussos: I ran the last campaign. We can speedrun this one.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no.
Gary Young: Don't put your drow in a box.
Wade: Oh.
Gary Young: is useful.
David Mendenhall: out.
Wade: Maybe you haven't looked up shadowboxing yet, because it would spoil things.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, it's just a… it's a technique for speedrunning.
Wade: You put a corpse in a box on a fiery patch of ground, and it completely fucks with the engine.
David Mendenhall: No.
Gary Young: Did they not?
Kostadis Roussos: Fix that bug?
Wade: I mean, it's been around since before, it was since, like, Original Sin, right?
David Mendenhall: Some… some instances of it, but not all.
Wade: Yeah.
Gary Young: I think I saw the 15-minute speedrun of the whole game that used that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Wade: Kill Shadowheart, put her in the box, throw the fire on the ground, throw the box.
David Mendenhall: Quite, quite inventive, actually.
Wade: Speedrunners are neat.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: Damn.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright, so I just read about… I just read about that glitch.
David Mendenhall: Shadowboxing.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I didn't realize it was literally Box Shadow Heart.
Wade: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: You put her in a box. You have to kill her to put her in a box in the middle of a cutscene, and….
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and it teleports you to the end of Act 2.
Wade: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Where you can, like, blow shit up with Gale.
Wade: You mean, blow Gale up.
Kostadis Roussos: But I don't… I blow shit up, I'm not… I'm not revealing anything. Oh, wait, you already know about.
David Mendenhall: He's an act 3, he's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: attack? Did you get TAC 3?
Gary Young: I am in the middle of Act 3.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Wade: Then you know Gale's whole story.
Gary Young: the lower city, and then the lower city has too much going on.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that was how I felt, too. It was very overwhelming. I actually, like, had to stop playing for a while. It was too overwhelming.
Wade: Oh, wow.
Kostadis Roussos: You don't have to finish everything.
Wade: Yeah, you do not have to side quest infinitely.
Gary Young: Breath-first search is.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, this is how Gary operates.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, not every quest has to be completed.
Wade: Yeah, I was sad I didn't finish The Clown.
Gary Young: I'm close to the third thing in town.
Wade: I wanted to.
David Mendenhall: Really?
Kostadis Roussos: finish the course.
David Mendenhall: It's, like, not even, like, a useful item that you get, it's, like, kind of a waste.
Wade: I don't know, it was at the end of it. I wanted to finish it, but I didn't… I missed, like, one or two body parts.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, they, they… Doesn't really make sense that somehow the clown ended up in all those different places.
David Mendenhall: Behind locked doors, and….
Kostadis Roussos: We're really having a con… I just want to make sure that we are currently….
Gary Young: I think we're talking about Oren, so, yes.
Wade: Yes, Orange.
Kostadis Roussos: We're talking about the… we're talking about a fantasy game in which
Kostadis Roussos: A deadly assassin can materialize out of nothing wearing.
David Mendenhall: any costume she wants, and we're discussing whether said deadly assassin, who's drenched in blood could drop body parts wherever she wants. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I just want to make sure that's what we're talking about.
Wade: Yes.
David Mendenhall: talking about.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, just double checking.
David Mendenhall: Got it.
Wade: chart.
David Mendenhall: Alright, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, so first of all, so first of all, there's the quest that, what's his name has?
Wade: Well, what's his name?
David Mendenhall: back to Phandalin and do some… do some research.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, I'm just saying, it's on your way, that's why.
David Mendenhall: Oh, we're doing a quest on the way?
Kostadis Roussos: I just wanted to point out that it was on the way.
David Mendenhall: What's on that?
Wade: Oh, on the way, not underway, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, on the way, yeah, yeah.
David Mendenhall: What's on the way? I guess I didn't realize there was something on the way.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so, what's her name? Adabra.
David Mendenhall: Adabra.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't.
Wade: The… the girl we had to bring home, the naturalist.
Kostadis Roussos: The Naturalist?
Wade: The nudist, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, da-da-da-da.
David Mendenhall: ….
Gary Young: She's the one that was in the house that we rescued.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah,
Wade: The one who didn't want to leave?
David Mendenhall: Is this written on the Quest Tracker?
Kostadis Roussos: It should have been, but it's not. It's, it's definitely a quest. As you guys were leaving Phandalin, she approached Soma, and, said, gave you guys a quest.
Wade: I mean, I remember some of the discussion. I do not appear to see it on the question.
David Mendenhall: There was Escort Alara and Jarek to Phandalin after an orc attack, which we did.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay, well, let me just… let me just remind you what the quest was.
Gary Young: Alright, cause I don't see it on the tracker.
Wade: Yeah, we failed our bookkeeping.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm, like, disappointed in you guys.
Wade: I'm disappointed in us, too.
David Mendenhall: Pretty good about the quests.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, you keep preventing some.
David Mendenhall: Occasionally, if it's a critical writer.
Gary Young: skill. What?
Gary Young: Occasionally use a critical failure on our bookkeeping skill.
Kostadis Roussos: Keep you on your toes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, where was this? ….
Wade: Alrighty.
David Mendenhall: Is this Mountain's Toe Gold Mine?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, where was it? I need to go find it.
Kostadis Roussos: So, ….
David Mendenhall: Actually, Leylon is kind of on the way.
Wade: Yeah, we should just stomp.
David Mendenhall: I mean, it's not that far off.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you can do whatever you want.
David Mendenhall: Could… I don't know, it'd be interesting to go to a different town.
David Mendenhall: Neverwinter's pretty far.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, yes. So, basically, Soma…
Kostadis Roussos: What's her name? Sorry, so let me go.
Wade: Adopra poda?
Wade: Adabra. Abracadabra.
David Mendenhall: Adoptra, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: … she remarked how there was an old grove that was just…
Kostadis Roussos: Past the Whispering Grove, so I'll just mark it here, so I'll just put you guys on the world map, so you know what I'm talking about. Yes, here it is.
Kostadis Roussos: There was the Whispering Grove.
Wade: It's spare one.
Gary Young: Whispering Grove.
David Mendenhall: Whispering Grove?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Gary Young: There's a path in there, or something?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, it's not, …
Kostadis Roussos: It was so vibrant, a testament to Shantae's blessing, deeming with life, but now it is dying. Not naturally, mind you, this isn't the slow dance of seasons, nor the honest bite of winter.
Kostadis Roussos: She says, There is a strange magical blight spreading through it. The trees twist in the natural waves, their leaves too bright or too sickly pale, as if… almost as if the colors are wrong.
Kostadis Roussos: And she then concludes, I have observed these dreadful signs, and I fear… That's…
Kostadis Roussos: Folks, that something is behind it. Whether it's the interventionists or something else, their constant meddling, their zealous rituals, and forceful cleansing around Vandolin and Leilon.
Kostadis Roussos: … Hmm, so….
Wade: Yeah, we did not put that.
David Mendenhall: Another curse.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so there'.
David Mendenhall: We're good at lifting curses.
Wade: Yeah, because it just involves killing stuff.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: They're like the Curse Busters.
David Mendenhall: How much money was involved in saving the Whispering Grove?
Wade: It's not about the money, it's about keeping the forests in check.
David Mendenhall: Dude, like, the forest is not gonna build my music studio.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, some….
David Mendenhall: Apparently, most of the treasure that we're… treasure that we're getting, I can't even use to build the music studio. So yes, I want to know how much
David Mendenhall: I need to assault the goddamn cursing.
Kostadis Roussos: Adabra did not have… make any monetary offer.
Wade: It's gonna be hard to get Vucard in on this one.
David Mendenhall: Phandalin'.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So you're not doing the quest. Okay.
Wade: Not on this trip.
Gary Young: Yeah, guess not.
Wade: It's a little out of the way.
Wade: Sure, we'll get closer to it later.
David Mendenhall: Actually, I don't see it on the map. Where is it?
Wade: It's north of Phandalin, it's the red….
Kostadis Roussos: It's on your way. It's literally on your way. Like, you literally are gonna come down the road, and you're just gonna take.
David Mendenhall: July?
Gary Young: There's, like, two legs of a triangle on our way.
Wade: Yeah, we're… we're headed east.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Wade: The Whispering Grove are north, east, and.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I see them now, Whispering Grove. It's like… Is this the same we had been hearing that the Neverwinter would?
David Mendenhall: That there was something… this is different than… we keep hearing that strange magic pervades Neverwinter Wood.
Kostadis Roussos: You've heard about that, too. These are unrelated questions.
David Mendenhall: separate issue.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Maybe if we talk to the guildmaster in town, or the mayor, or whatever his name is.
David Mendenhall: About the Whispering Grove, he'll have some more information.
David Mendenhall: I don't… who is a Adabra, anyway? We don't really know who she is.
Wade: She was the daughter of some noble, wasn't she?
Kostadis Roussos: Adabra was the woman who was at Umbrage Hill, who was the lady who you rescued from the town and gave you extra money for helping and convinced what's-His-Name to give you extra money.
David Mendenhall: Oh, oh!
Kostadis Roussos: That's suck.
David Mendenhall: Adabra. Oh, okay. Adabra is the one that we… is the….
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it's the old lady who
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and so she was kind of hoping that, you know, one good turn would lead to another, but clearly that….
David Mendenhall: I see.
Wade: Vukradin is not motivated by good turns.
David Mendenhall: the mid ones.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: the midwife.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Wade: I can't remember that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, among many others, she was also an herbalist.
David Mendenhall: But she and I had a connection when we.
Kostadis Roussos: Cheers.
David Mendenhall: She understood…
David Mendenhall: what I was trying to do, and that I needed organic fair trade gold. Yeah. Yeah, she offered me nothing?
Kostadis Roussos: But then what happened was you decided to go work for the Order of the Gauntlet, and she stopped talking to you and talked to Soma.
Wade: Yeah.
Wade: She's got Soma's ear.
David Mendenhall: I'm not so sure about the Order of the Gauntlet.
Gary Young: After… after that.
David Mendenhall: random attack.
David Mendenhall: That seemed like they knew exactly where we were going.
David Mendenhall: So she's not….
Gary Young: circumstantiality.
David Mendenhall: You're telling me Adabra's not a fan of the Order of the Gauntlet.
Kostadis Roussos: What you know is that you have to roll your… yes, you know that she… after she… you started wearing your pin.
David Mendenhall: She became a lot less interested in you and only spoke to Soma. In fact, she spoke to Soma privately.
David Mendenhall: Well, maybe this is why I don't remember this conversation at all.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I know, we… I… Doesn't matter. Maybe that's why it's not on the quest tracker.
Wade: It was probably on me to write it down.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, anyway.
Wade: Okay. Yeah, that's my bad.
David Mendenhall: The pin is gone. I don't know about this quest, so as far as I'm concerned, we're going to Phandalin.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The rest of you want to go?
Gary Young: Sure.
Gary Young: It's a fan of it.
Wade: Yeah.
Wade: Someone's not gonna make waves.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, to Phantom Events.
Wade: She guides people where they want to go. You know, guiding, tour guide, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you arrive in Phandalin.
Kostadis Roussos: -
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, sorry, I did not….
Wade: It has not changed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You are in Pendulum.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Do we need to go back to the…
Gary Young: the mayor, and talk with him about the, White House.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. So you….
David Mendenhall: The Town Master? Is that his name?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it's time.
David Mendenhall: semester.
Wade: The guy who always has a, you know, has a locked door.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's got a lot.
David Mendenhall: It assumes we're dragons.
Wade: Do we have, like, a secret knock for them yet? Like….
Kostadis Roussos: Powerful.
Gary Young: Agreed.
Kostadis Roussos: Put his name there, so we have it. Alright. So, …
Kostadis Roussos: You arrive at Harbin's… you arrive at the… in Phandalin.
Kostadis Roussos: ….
Gary Young: While you're there….
Kostadis Roussos: … Let's get her out.
Kostadis Roussos: Secure our team.
Kostadis Roussos: Adabra sees you.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I mean… Approaches the four of you.
Kostadis Roussos: And we'll give Harbin… Oh, it's the impairment of the night coming as well.
David Mendenhall: Who?
Kostadis Roussos: I harbor in an icon so that we have all the characters on the board.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Adabra… … sees, notices you coming into town. It's a small town, and …
Kostadis Roussos: She, steps out and asks,
Kostadis Roussos: asks, to ask Soma, so, did you visit the, Whispering Grove?
Wade: No, we haven't quite made it into our journeys yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm. She goes, well… She looks at you a little bit curious. She goes, why not?
Gary Young: her way.
Wade: It was a little out of the way while we were out, you know, clearing out other blights on the land.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay. Well, she goes, I see, I see.
Wade: There's a lot of it going around.
Kostadis Roussos: She then looks at you and says, This is important.
Wade: This is not… this is important work, Soma.
Kostadis Roussos: If we let… if we let these changes happen.
Gary Young: The balance, the natural balance, will be disturbed.
Kostadis Roussos: She then goes, please, please take care of this, and then she walks away.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Adabra, before you walk away.
Wade: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes?
David Mendenhall: … Can I talk to you about something?
Wade: She looks at you, of course. What would you need? A token of… a token of good health? Is there a woman in some… in a family way that needs to be taken care of?
David Mendenhall: midwife.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, you know….
David Mendenhall: about the Order of the Gauntlet.
Kostadis Roussos: Do I know about the Order of the Gauntlet?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I know many things about the order. She goes, she looks at you, goes, why would you want to know?
Kostadis Roussos: She then notices you don't have a pin. Whatever happened to your PIN?
David Mendenhall: It was broken in a battle.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, we're not, ….
Wade: I thought you were using that as planted evidence.
David Mendenhall: No.
Wade: Okay.
David Mendenhall: It was bro- it was lost, lost in the battle.
David Mendenhall: Whoa.
Gary Young: Sounds like a cat.
Wade: Pat found a toy.
Gary Young: The cat comes into the room, closes the door, and then cat reopened the door, and so she has realized that if she…
Gary Young: place with the doorstop, then it summons the human to open the door for her. Smart guy.
Wade: chat.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Adabra looks at you and goes.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I think they're a fine organization, why do you ask?
David Mendenhall: I just don't know very much about them.
Kostadis Roussos: What's there to know?
David Mendenhall: They seem very mysterious.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, they're not mysterious, they're quite… quite… they're quite transparent.
David Mendenhall: Really?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes.
David Mendenhall: where can I learn more about this transparent Organization, if.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's quite transparent, what they want. Their view is that the world could be made better.
Kostadis Roussos: They want to make the world better. They seem to think that the world is in imbalance, and that by making it better, things will get better.
Kostadis Roussos: Instead of recognizing that the world is fine just the way it is, and that in their attempts to make things better, they make things worse.
Kostadis Roussos: There's… theirs is an ideology of change for the better. What happens when you change it for the better? Why do things get better? No, the worse things get more powerful and more dangerous. The more you… the more you push along one… up one road, the worse it gets along another.
Kostadis Roussos: They are committed… they are committed to the foolish path of imbalance.
Wade: You don't suppose they're the ones messing with the Whispering Grove.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, hmm… The Whispering Grove.
Kostadis Roussos: … there she goes, the Whispering Grove.
Kostadis Roussos: I would be… no, no, the Whispering Grove is not… I do not believe it is caused by the Whispering Grove. I believe it is caused as a result of the interventionists
Kostadis Roussos: meddling in affairs they should not be.
Wade: Hmm… Might have been a nice angle.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, oh, the order of the lords, sorry, the order of the gauntlet, they're too busy chasing dragons and killing orcs and trying to clear the land for civilization.
Kostadis Roussos: slaughtering monsters, at least with normal adventures, they slaughter a monster and take its treasures. These ones slaughter a monster and move on, or donate it to some charity in which they again tried to do good.
Kostadis Roussos: They're always….
Gary Young: I mean, like, all that good, good treasure.
Kostadis Roussos: They're, they're….
David Mendenhall: committed to neutrality. Really committed.
Wade: So beautiful, yet so neutral.
Kostadis Roussos: She's like, they are… they are… theirs is a path of madness.
David Mendenhall: Madness.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, is it not mad to not see that the universe itself, the multiverse itself, is one thing? That there isn't good, and there isn't evil, there's just the thing?
Kostadis Roussos: And that she is… and that the order of the gauntlet is committed to its path?
Kostadis Roussos: I… Soma understands this, and I thought you did.
David Mendenhall: Some of you understand that there's… There's neither good nor evil.
Wade: I understand that all things are, you know… Temporary.
Kostadis Roussos: I did not say there's no such thing as a good act or an evil act, but the idea that by striving, one can force the world to be better, good or evil. Well, one can do that, but what happens is that the evil will then have to respond, and it won't respond
Kostadis Roussos: Gently, it will respond with full force. The more you push in one direction, the bigger the reaction in the other direction is. And isn't our goal to maintain the symbiosis of the multiverse? Instead, what happens is the worlds fall apart.
David Mendenhall: Maybe we really should have left you in that house.
Wade: Oh, you do not like her.
David Mendenhall: Well, I mean, why did we go save her?
David Mendenhall: Per 50 GP? She doesn't want… she doesn't want good.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, she pauses and says, my dear friend, Vukradin.
Kostadis Roussos: As you recall, I wish to be left alone in my house, but you insisted…
Kostadis Roussos: You did insist I come here, and then when you asked for more money from Harbin, did I not intervene to get you more money?
David Mendenhall: You did.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and weren't the… and why did I do this? Because….
David Mendenhall: Why did we do it?
Kostadis Roussos: Because this was… this is not about good or evil, it's about seeing balance, and I saw the balance of your just cause.
Kostadis Roussos: You are devoted to music. You are not devoted to
Kostadis Roussos: changing evil or changing harm. Music is part of the music of the universe.
Kostadis Roussos: You are not a…
Kostadis Roussos: A devotee of the powers of good, or even the devotee of the powers of evil.
Gary Young: Music.
David Mendenhall: I'm good.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I thought, I thought of someone who was so passionate about music, that you would see the world as Soma and I do.
Kostadis Roussos: Instead, I notice by your choice of alliances that you see things very differently than me.
David Mendenhall: Okay, I'm done talking to her. She's being patronizing.
David Mendenhall: See ya.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, very well. I hope… I hope you… I hope you'll take care of the issues of the Whispering Grove, otherwise the things will get worse.
Wade: I'll work on him.
David Mendenhall: I don't know. Maybe we shouldn't disturb the natural order.
Wade: The natural order is actively being disturbed.
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly, says the Adabra.
Kostadis Roussos: It is act… it is actively being disturbed.
Wade: I just like to know who's doing it when we get a chance.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope. So… … alright, so Adabra looks at you and says, could I sell you any potions of healing?
Wade: I think we're alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Well then, if you need anything from me, I will just be over here. Alright.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, where else do you want to go?
Gary Young: Do we have any treasure to sell?
Wade: There's some octopus hide armor, right?
David Mendenhall: I think, I would like to invest… I would like to talk to some shopkeepers about all of this blood loot we found, and is there a way to identify… are there, like, markings on it that would indicate where it came from, or…
David Mendenhall: Maybe we should… are there any markings that indicate any sort of points of origin, or anything like that that could be helpful?
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, they all turn to you and say, that's what identify spells are for.
Wade: Hmm.
David Mendenhall: Okay, where's some of those?
Kostadis Roussos: She couldn't go, I… you need to go find a magic user for one of those.
Wade: Can we just get some scrolls?
Kostadis Roussos: And LionShield Coaster says, well, I don't happen to have some identify scrolls today, but if you give me a few days, I could probably… I could probably dig some up, or at least find you a bead on someone who could do it, or find you the name of a magic user who could help.
David Mendenhall: Probably we're going to need a magic user who's willing to… Do this pro bono?
David Mendenhall: I don't know to pay a lot of money? To teach Corbin to….
Wade: You identify scrap spells.
Kostadis Roussos: Or, or, or, or, or, you know, you could go talk to your, friend, the, …
Kostadis Roussos: Ser Kaelen, the, ….
David Mendenhall: or Karen, who betrayed me? I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: Not a big time.
David Mendenhall: Right now.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know whether he betrayed you?
David Mendenhall: I… suspect that he did.
Wade: … You don't want to confront him about it?
David Mendenhall: Well, he's not here, right? Didn't he leave town?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he stayed in town.
Wade: You said town.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Corbin just….
Gary Young: Multiclass send to a wizard.
Kostadis Roussos: Who did?
Gary Young: We should have Corbin multi-class into a wizard.
Wade: Orc. Yeah, so we can do our, our, identify spells.
Gary Young: Yes.
David Mendenhall: He's a lackey that hangs out at camp and casts buff spells on us.
Kostadis Roussos: That's right, that's right.
Wade: Don't underestimate his contribution.
Kostadis Roussos: Do not underestimate his contribution.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, … where would you like to go… would you like to go to the tavern?
David Mendenhall: Was there any sort of… was there anyone… who gave us the quest for the Tower of Storms?
Kostadis Roussos: Nobody gave you the quest for the Tower of Storms, you heard a rumor and you followed it.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Wade: Doesn't sound like us.
Gary Young: Well, I… it…
Gary Young: It does seem like you should still tell the, the town keeper, because he will need to, you know, see if he wants to keep the, the lighthouse, stocked and….
David Mendenhall: Oh, that's a good point. Yeah, keep the fire going, maybe appoint a new master of the lighthouse to take care of it.
Gary Young: They need to hire a light keeper.
David Mendenhall: We do.
Gary Young: Glorious Lightkeeper.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
David Mendenhall: Alright, that's a good idea, that's a good idea.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on that.
Kostadis Roussos: I love it. Alright, so to Court Harbin Master.
Kostadis Roussos: to Harbin.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like… Harbin, … Sarban sees you guys, and is like, well!
Gary Young: What a wonderful… what a wonderful surprise to see you all!
Gary Young: Yeah, … Talos? Did you realize there was an infestation of Talos in, you know, like, on the coast?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you funny. We have dragons, and now we have Talos?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's… that's quite awful.
Kostadis Roussos: That is… that is very awful.
Gary Young: But we did sanctify the altar.
Gary Young: No marks.
Kostadis Roussos: You did?
Gary Young: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, there's no more Talos.
Gary Young: Yeah, no more talents.
David Mendenhall: Well, no, but we need to go investigate in Leilan.
David Mendenhall: There's… there's more going on there.
Gary Young: Well, not at the White House.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, the lighthouse is good, but Leylon… the Talos worship may continue.
Gary Young: Oh. But there's no one working the lighthouse, so the light will eventually go out. And light is important.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: …
Kostadis Roussos: Harbin goes, I think Lord Neverwinter will be delighted to find out that you have managed to cleanse the lighthouse of the evildoers who had taken ownership of it, and I will make sure to send him a note.
Gary Young: Thank you. Make sure you put in a good word for us.
Kostadis Roussos: I will absolutely put in a great resource.
David Mendenhall: to Neverwinter and take it to him personally?
Kostadis Roussos: You could, I suppose. I don't know whether he'd want to see you, but he's a very busy man. If this is something you wish to do, far be it for me to say anything.
Gary Young: I mean, there are problems within the town, and, you know, you did sign up to come and help here, and.
Kostadis Roussos: If you're going back to Lord Neverwinter while the town is still in a state of disrepair, it's not quite clear what… how he'll react. But far be it from me to tell you what to do.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, he's a lord of a large city, you're a third-level character.
Kostadis Roussos: You know….
David Mendenhall: We're not very… we're not very….
Wade: We don't rate.
David Mendenhall: We did agree to come here, and… Yes, and so….
Kostadis Roussos: That's a good point.
Gary Young: And he's like, you could go there.
Kostadis Roussos: Any….
David Mendenhall: It doesn't send you back.
Kostadis Roussos: Or, or worse.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, with, like, withdraw your tax-free status, and send you back.
David Mendenhall: Alright, maybe we should go talk to Ser Kaelen.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just do something here…
Kostadis Roussos: Like, something I need to do here.
Kostadis Roussos: To just find something. Give me, give me one second…
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Okey-dokey.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you go to, Ser Kaelen, yes?
David Mendenhall: Should've came….
Kostadis Roussos: Ser Kaelen is sitting there and is looking really happy to see you.
Kostadis Roussos: Spider-man is also looking happy to see you.
Wade: Why is he happy to see us?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, because, you know, Vukradin played some music that was very successful in the pub. You know, he got to tell his story about how…
Kostadis Roussos: … How… he got his nickname of Spider-Man.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, he, he, he, he… He likes… He likes it, man.
Wade: Business, got it.
Kostadis Roussos: you're good for business, you're working on the problems of the area. I mean, these are all good things. Why wouldn't… plus, you know, you're helping clear the area of evil agents.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So, like, from his perspective, why wouldn't he… … Alright.
David Mendenhall: We're back!
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Ser Kaelen is delighted to see.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, I, Vukradin, how was your… were you able to achieve victory in… and secure the tower from its, the evil… the evil that was there?
Kostadis Roussos: Baza's, was there evil there? Remember, we said there were 3 options.
David Mendenhall: It was evil.
Wade: There was Talos.
Kostadis Roussos: Talos. Talos. He goes, Paul pauses and says, Now that is of grave concern.
Kostadis Roussos: Talos? Was it one… was it… was it… was… there was… was there anything else strange about Talos? Was Cleric of Talos?
Wade: He had a hole in his chest.
Kostadis Roussos: A hole in his chest.
Wade: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: He hadn't used his… he had illuminated his heart and used it to light the lighthouse.
Kostadis Roussos: Because this is very strange. A typical shaman of Talos could not do such things. There's some hidden force deeper here.
David Mendenhall: There were hockeys, too.
Wade: Yeah, we didn't find any greater force there that we noticed.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, there's… who knows what's going on? There's so many different…
Kostadis Roussos: This… ever since the end of the War of the Giants and the War of the Dragons, this whole area's been in a state of chaos. Many of my brethren died fighting the dragons. Several died fighting the barbarians. But, sorry, the….
David Mendenhall: Something happened, though, along the way to the tower that I need to ask you about.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, what?
David Mendenhall: We were ambushed.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… My goodness. By whom?
David Mendenhall: Someone who knew… someone who knew we were coming.
Kostadis Roussos: … he denies… he denies it.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's telling the truth, actually.
David Mendenhall: But who would have known that we… but who would have known that we were coming?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't see….
Gary Young: Like, we've been very secretive.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Ser Kaelen goes, let me see. He raises his hand. Who knew that these individuals were willing to go to the Tower of the…
Kostadis Roussos: In this bar.
Kostadis Roussos: People raise their head. Somebody goes, we were taking bets on whether all four would come back, or whether they would ditch the barn.
Wade: Anyway, shouldn't we get a cut of those bets?
David Mendenhall: I think… I think we're gonna need to be more secretive.
Kostadis Roussos: Spider… Spider-Man… Spider-Man points to a budding pool.
David Mendenhall: What are you guys betting we'll do next?
Kostadis Roussos: ….
Wade: Tell us the odds, and we'll, you know, wreck the curve.
David Mendenhall: Get in on this?
Wade: We'll take a dive, don't we?
David Mendenhall: If I win, this is fair trade gold.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: It's still a little shadily gotten, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: So, so they, they… And not stolen. Yeah, so, so, so, so, so, Spider-Man says, you know, Vukradin, you're a good sport.
Kostadis Roussos: And… and the betting pool was that, they would kill you.
Kostadis Roussos: Because they couldn't stay.
Kostadis Roussos: You're patronizing.
Kostadis Roussos: You're a patronizing Toad.
Wade: It's a shame, he actually came.
David Mendenhall: in handy.
Kostadis Roussos: Although he goes, but I want you to know that I believe that your musical inspiration
Kostadis Roussos: Would cause everyone, the team, to rally behind you.
Kostadis Roussos: And I want you to know I won the pool, so he gives you 10 gold pieces.
Wade: There you go, 10 fair trade goals!
Kostadis Roussos: It gives you 10 gold pieces.
David Mendenhall: I needed that.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, gives you 10 gold pieces, and then says, but dude, I think the only person who didn't know you were going to the Tower of the Storms was the dead.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, the truly dead, not the partially dead, or the undead, or the coming back….
David Mendenhall: Alright, we're gonna be more secretive about… alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Just to be clear, you had a big shouting match in the middle of the town. You declared….
David Mendenhall: I don't remember doing that, but okay, maybe I did.
Gary Young: Definitely not going….
David Mendenhall: Did I… did I work it into the music?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no.
David Mendenhall: What happened was that….
Kostadis Roussos: barged up to Harvard and said, How do I destroy a tower?
Gary Young: Briefly ran away.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, well, we talked to Harbin about it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but in the middle of the square, it was… it was not… this was not a private and discreet conversation.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Alright. I have a couple more questions for Ser Kaelen.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, absolutely, sir.
David Mendenhall: … Adopt.
Kostadis Roussos: is not a.
David Mendenhall: Do you know a… do you know Adabra?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, she's a wonderful woman.
David Mendenhall: She doesn't care so much for you and your organization.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, well… There's… that's what I said, she is, she is, she is, …
Kostadis Roussos: A member of the Emerald Gauntlet… the Emerald…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, she is one of the Emerald Enclave.
Kostadis Roussos: And the order of the Gauntlet and the Emerald Enclave have allied at times when great evil has faced the realms?
Kostadis Roussos: There's always the…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, not presently. There's no great force. We defeated the giants, the war with the barbarians… sorry, the endless wars that occurred after the defeat of the barbarians.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, keep stumbling over this. Let's just say the end of the wars of the giants. How about we phrase it that way? The end of the wars of the giants.
Kostadis Roussos: He's trying not to offend Brewbarry.
Kostadis Roussos: …
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, the only… the last time that we agreed to work together was during the, …
Kostadis Roussos: when Tiamat showed up.
David Mendenhall: It's quite a while ago.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so Tiamat showed up. It was a very surprising… we were all very surprised when they showed up. Everyone had said that the order of the Emerald Enclave would not arrive.
Kostadis Roussos: But, one of the heroes of the War of the Giants was able to convince one of their leaders, who brought a faction of the Emerald Enclave, whose trance served a definitive… served as a definitive force that helped us defeat the armies outside of the Well of the Dragons.
Kostadis Roussos: And so…
Kostadis Roussos: And so the Emerald Enclave and the Order of the Gauntlet are friends, even though we do not always see eye to eye.
Kostadis Roussos: There is… we… and then he pauses… they believe that there is some mythical balance that needs to be maintained.
Kostadis Roussos: We believe that… that if you do not… if you do not strive for good, the mythical balance will crush everything that is beautiful, and it goes off and on and on and on about his, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: I could give you the speed.
Wade: beliefs that there's a, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: A better cause.
Wade: universal good.
David Mendenhall: yes, universal good, and the importance of heroism, and acts of heroism. Oh, I think, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so he says he's, you know.
David Mendenhall: Writing for what's right has meaning… has intrinsic meaning.
David Mendenhall: Right, so yeah, he's very much a fighting for what's right. Well, let's be clear, Adabra's also fighting for what she thinks is right. She thinks she's right. No, but she thinks there's no… nothing that's truly right or truly evil, so there's that too.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that's not true. She believes that… that she believes that the felon.
Wade: It is neutral.
Kostadis Roussos: She believes the balance is intrinsically good.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so I just want to be clear, it's not that she doesn't believe there's any evil or good.
Wade: Like, part Jedi.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So yeah, so yeah, Ser Kaelen is as surprised as you are about this ambush. He goes, he does mention that there is all sorts of… he's worried. He does mention that he's concerned because there has been tales of bandits in the area.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, have you heard anything about the carver?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… Well, I've heard that he looks at you and says.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's why I'm still in town.
David Mendenhall: What do you mean?
Wade: What?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, well, there's a rumor of a new bandit leader who's taken a residence around here called the Carver.
David Mendenhall: Any idea where?
Kostadis Roussos: No. No, that's what I was hoping, you know, I would get an agent. That would be you.
Kostadis Roussos: And, we would… We would find out where he was, and then we'd call in the cavalry.
Gary Young: Oh, okay. That's didn't even know where it came from.
David Mendenhall: Okay, so we just need to do some recon, and then you'll… you'll… Flush them out.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, yes, if that's what's necessary?
David Mendenhall: Interesting, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: ….
David Mendenhall: recon mission.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, he goes, but I… we don't have any… we don't know anything about him, other than there have been, organized raids.
Kostadis Roussos: And some of the… some of the humanoids.
David Mendenhall: Seemed a little bit more organized these days than normal.
Gary Young: What if we knew someone that had worked for him?
Wade: We just happen to have one.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that would be excellent. Would he be a high-ranking member of the group?
Wade: He'd probably be the lowest lackey imaginable.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. No….
David Mendenhall: Pretty sure he doesn't.
Wade: I think he's still got trainee on his armor.
David Mendenhall: I think he's told us everything he knows, and he doesn't know anything.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so now, so Kalen goes, one of the challenges of this Carver individual, most bandits like to brag and strut their stuff and let everybody know who they are, and that makes them relatively straightforward to find. You cast some clairvoyant spells…
Kostadis Roussos: And they're quickly identified. This one seems to be a little bit cleverer than that.
Kostadis Roussos: He's been hiding his… he's been hiding himself. He's been hiding himself. Hiding behind a name, hiding behind the deadly acts of violence of his crew.
David Mendenhall: I wonder if he's kind of like the Dread Pirate Robert.
Gary Young: And, do you know anything about the Whispering Grove?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, the Whispering Grove. Who do I know about the Whispering Grove? Let me just check.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… …
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so actually, I did make a slight mistake on its location.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: I… I was wrong.
Kostadis Roussos: It's actually closer to Phandalin. That was my mistake.
Wade: Oh, yeah, I mean, you put it pretty far out of our.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, no, it wasn't supposed to be that far, so hold on. Let me just do this. Let me just make a map. I'm gonna just draw an ellipse.
Kostadis Roussos: So… Over here.
Wade: The blue circle?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'm gonna make it green.
David Mendenhall: Oh, that's very close.
Wade: Yeah, we're literally there, like….
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's like… it's… It's up.
Wade: outside fan.
David Mendenhall: That's like an hour's walk.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, sorry, it was… I was, like, going, like, why is this, like… like, this seemed, like, wrong, so I apologize for that.
Wade: That's okay.
David Mendenhall: Well, do you know anything about it?
Kostadis Roussos: Damn.
David Mendenhall: for Kalen?
Wade: Yeah, that's close enough that someone can just go out on her own if the party doesn't go along, like, it's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, alright, so, what does he know about the Whispering Grove? Okay, let me just see, what does he know?
Kostadis Roussos: Well… He goes, the Withering… the Whispering Grove…
Kostadis Roussos: Was a charming little area nearby.
Kostadis Roussos: That people used to go to, … Relax…
Kostadis Roussos: There was a nice little… there was a little bit of trees, it was a nice little bit of shade you could get in the… in the hilly area around here.
Kostadis Roussos: I was well-respected, but, …
Kostadis Roussos: … something… something's gone… something's happened over the last few… has been happening over the last few months, and people just don't go there anymore.
Wade: Can you describe this something?
Kostadis Roussos: she… he goes, to be quite honest with you, I haven't really gone there, and the Adabra's been… always been saying that there's some kind of…
Kostadis Roussos: change to the world there, that there is, like, there's some kind of blight, and so I kind of ascribed it to the kind of thing, since nobody was… had gotten hurt.
Kostadis Roussos: and we… I was dealing with higher… we were dealing with higher priority issues. I really didn't want to spend time on what felt like an internal matter of the Emerald Enclave about a bunch of trees.
Kostadis Roussos: having blight.
Wade: Concerned that the blight will spread.
Kostadis Roussos: No, he's not.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He's… but he goes… it… it is, …
Kostadis Roussos: It's, … it is what it is.
Kostadis Roussos: He does say… he goes, the townspeople would be grateful for you if you were to go deal with it. Ever since… ever since this blight, people haven't been going there.
Gary Young: Are there any mages that live nearby?
Kostadis Roussos: … mages living nearby. What level mage do you need?
Wade: What level is identical.
David Mendenhall: I'm working on that. Looks like… oh, identify as a first level spell? I could probably just learn it.
Kostadis Roussos: You were gonna say, Gary, what, what… What are you looking for?
Gary Young: Oh, is that the identify spell?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay, yeah.
Gary Young: Okay. Well….
David Mendenhall: I'm….
Gary Young: you know, if Whispering Grove is trouble, and it's so close to town, then it seems like a priority to me.
David Mendenhall: I do have access to identify.
Wade: There we go, that is definitely on-brand for you to have.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that one definitely sounds like….
Gary Young: And I have Locate Object, although it seems to work in reverse.
David Mendenhall: It'll drop.
Wade: I have mending, so I can put things back in lighter order.
Kostadis Roussos: As he's… as he's muttering, he goes.
Kostadis Roussos: quite honestly, the thing that I don't take seriously about Sobez is that she claims there's some kind of
Kostadis Roussos: Interplanar interference related to this grove.
Kostadis Roussos: And the most ridiculous things I've heard in my life.
Wade: We have an interplanar being right before you, like….
Kostadis Roussos: Which one?
Wade: Isn't, Vukradin, half Celestial or whatever?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, he goes, there's many interplay now. This one worships a cleric, that one worships a god, this one worships a power. I'm… she claims that there's some kind of…
Kostadis Roussos: peculiar, magical, planar event. Quite honestly, I think she's gone mad. Some of them Emerald Enclave, after the intervention against Tiamat, have declared that the.
David Mendenhall: Demons themselves are part of the natural world.
Wade: And nobody's going to actually check it out that you've heard directly from, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, it's a few hours out of town, nobody's been bothered.
Kostadis Roussos: we have a dragon flying about. You know, part of the reason we never went… Lord never sent out that check for people to go find monsters was because we didn't have people to go do that.
Wade: Hmm.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Wade: You guys need help.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, well, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: this week.
Kostadis Roussos: Ser Kaelen goes… Ser Kaelen goes, yes, yes, we do.
Kostadis Roussos: the, the, the.
Wade: Do you know how to acquire help?
Wade: Did you know that money helps get help?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but the order of the gauntlet is not like the Harpers, which have resorted to hiring
Kostadis Roussos: Hiring people to augment their ranks.
David Mendenhall: Weird.
David Mendenhall: The Harpers will hire me?
Wade: Expect everyone to work for free, got it.
David Mendenhall: Do you know where I can contact them?
Wade: Oh, no.
Wade: Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you actually say that?
Wade: No, no, this is Wade saying that.
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, no, I'm saying? Does he actually say that?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, yes, I've met a Harper agent, I'm sure that one will pass by this town at some point in time.
Kostadis Roussos: Just look for… just look for the person who's running away from the danger and taking notes of it.
David Mendenhall: And then sending me in.
David Mendenhall: With a pocket full of gold.
Kostadis Roussos: He thinks this is very funny, right? He doesn't realize that you're being serious.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, next thing you're going to tell me is you want to go work for the Zhentarim.
Wade: No.
David Mendenhall: They… all of their… all of their gold is stolen.
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly.
Wade: You should just join the Emerald Enclave, where gold doesn't really mean anything.
David Mendenhall: Won't build me my music studio.
Wade: Shhh.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so apparently I do have an Identify spell, so I can cast Identify on all of these objects.
David Mendenhall: So we can… we can get that information. I don't know why I didn't realize that earlier.
Wade: Okay.
David Mendenhall: I thought it was higher level.
Wade: It's not like you forgot you could shoot two arrows or something.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so this apparently is only supposed to tell you about magic… what magic.
David Mendenhall: No, I read that, yeah. I don't know if you want to bend the rules, or if, if you want to do something else, or if.
Kostadis Roussos: Everything.
David Mendenhall: Not possible to get this information.
David Mendenhall: Also, technically, every cast requires a pearl worth 100 gold pieces, so….
Kostadis Roussos: I think… I mean, here's….
David Mendenhall: So, go….
Kostadis Roussos: Here's what I'll do. You get the standard, you get what it says.
Kostadis Roussos: without any magical item. But if you want the augmented historical.
David Mendenhall: In fact, it burned.
Kostadis Roussos: Because I have to….
David Mendenhall: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want me to tell you why? Because the GM then has to go and prevent it.
David Mendenhall: You can burn the blood money.
Gary Young: That's… that's the TPU cost.
Wade: Yeah, there's no, ….
Kostadis Roussos: I have to… I have to go into ChatGPT and start… Give me a backpack.
David Mendenhall: story for this item, this armor, this… Or somewhere there's a server burning lots of coal to give you an answer on this one, Mendenhall.
David Mendenhall: You're gonna have to pay for that call.
Gary Young: That's why the data center should be nuclear-powered.
David Mendenhall: There you go. Or solar.
Wade: Or Kalos-powered, I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: Talus… I'm a big fan of TELUS Power. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: …
Kostadis Roussos: What… so what's your… so what are you gonna do? Are you gonna burn a pearl worth 100 gold pieces?
David Mendenhall: That would not be consistent with my….
Kostadis Roussos: No.
David Mendenhall: plan to build a music studio. I mean, morally, I would be okay with using the blood money, but that would really betray my friends here.
Wade: Same we didn't find any pearls at all.
David Mendenhall: I don't think I'm quite… I'm quite that selfish at this point.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: We did find gems, but we… I don't think we found.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I did not find 100 GP parole.
David Mendenhall: No, we did not.
Kostadis Roussos: So, so, so, so I'm gonna go with 100… Oh, we did find 6 pearls of 100 GP each. We did.
David Mendenhall: It's on the… it is actually on the tracker. 6 cells of 100 GP each.
Wade: Yeah?
Kostadis Roussos: Sounds good.
David Mendenhall: Jones.
Kostadis Roussos: Good job.
Wade: generating.
David Mendenhall: What are the chances, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: The universe hates me.
David Mendenhall: I still… I… I… I… I'm starting to feel the conflict of the train by friends.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, you don't have to make a decision now, remember?
Kostadis Roussos: And you could also ask, what's his name, whether he could help you get that information.
David Mendenhall: Ser Kaelen?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I could ask him. Yay, we found all of this… Treasurer.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, do you tell them about the boats and the names of the boats?
Gary Young: Yeah, sure.
Wade: Yeah….
David Mendenhall: I don't remember the name. I wasn't sure I trusted him enough, but you're gonna tell him.
Kostadis Roussos: So he says, that's all very interesting. I will have to take some notes and ask around.
Kostadis Roussos: Come back in a few days, and maybe I will have something for you.
Kostadis Roussos: And he pauses and says, it's a good thing that we have people like you who are concerned with returning the stolen goods to their rightful owners instead of taking them as if the dead are to be robbed.
Gary Young: Yeah, and we'll have to make sure that they, you know, know what secret code was on the inside of the chest.
Kostadis Roussos: What'd you say? What were you trying to say?
Gary Young: What the secret code was on the inside of the chest.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: What? He looks at you… what secret code?
David Mendenhall: There's a secret code on the inside of the chest?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: You're just making shit up.
David Mendenhall: You're trying to throw them off.
Kostadis Roussos: Is making shit up, yeah.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Should we just leave town without saying anything, or should we purposely tell people we're going somewhere else?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, hold on, so there's also the small matter of…
Kostadis Roussos: You know, you're gonna have to spend the night, because it's kind of like….
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Wade: Journey, yeah, that's fine.
Gary Young: Go to the Whispering Grove in the… at night, no.
Kostadis Roussos: So….
Gary Young: Sleep sounds good.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Let's play some music.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you able to play some music?
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry will be entertained.
David Mendenhall: Let's see how it goes.
David Mendenhall: Feeling good.
Wade: It's not too shabby!
David Mendenhall: We're rockin' tonight.
David Mendenhall: I should make some money, that was such a good performance.
David Mendenhall: Should get some gold pieces thrown at me.
David Mendenhall: Early silver.
Wade: Making it hail.
David Mendenhall: Making it rain.
Kostadis Roussos: Two silver pieces, our oldest.
David Mendenhall: Pillar pieces. Well, yeah!
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled the D20.
Kostadis Roussos: I was like, okay, 1 to 20 silver pieces.
David Mendenhall: I'll take them.
Wade: It's hard.
David Mendenhall: And, we no longer have to pay for the room, so that's nice.
Gary Young: Are we all playing together?
David Mendenhall: Sure, you guys can jam with me.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, just to be clear, when… well, if… Valphine is dancing with you.
Kostadis Roussos: Remember, she balances out your complex music with her drow skills, so that increases the payload.
Gary Young: Halo?
David Mendenhall: She makes… she makes… she's more of a pop number.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, what happens is that, as a result, the music is enjoyed by more people, right? Yeah, exactly.
David Mendenhall: Bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Rukrigdin plays a very subtle kind of music that doesn't appeal to the masses, which is why….
David Mendenhall: Yeah, so I've found, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so he only gets one D20.
Kostadis Roussos: But, when he plays with… Valphine, he gets 2 D20s worth of stuff.
David Mendenhall: Cool, what'd we get?
Kostadis Roussos: ….
Gary Young: Brewbarry and Velveen both got 14s.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm rolling the… oh, you rolled 14s. Okay, yeah, so you've got another 8 silver pieces.
David Mendenhall: Wow. Oh, right. That's, like, the equivalent of a whole gold piece.
Kostadis Roussos: So there's.
Wade: Okay, it's.
David Mendenhall: Really moving up in the ranks!
Gary Young: Did you add the bunny already?
David Mendenhall: I did, yeah.
Gary Young: Okay, great.
David Mendenhall: 10 silvers.
Gary Young: Period.
David Mendenhall: Right.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so is it morning?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, hold on.
David Mendenhall: Was the town ransacked overnight?
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: I know I'm gonna regret this, but what the hell?
Wade: Oh, dear.
Kostadis Roussos: Boop, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And it said, I know I'm gonna regret this.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you wake up in the morning and find inside of your room, just make sure….
David Mendenhall: A Harper agent?
Wade: No, the Zentaurum, come on.
David Mendenhall: Zentarim!
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Find the letter addressed to you.
Kostadis Roussos: To Vukrad, Vucherdinn.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I find the letter addressed to me?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Oh, dear.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you read it? I shared it with every….
Wade: I'm reading it.
Wade: Sh-should I not be reading it?
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming….
David Mendenhall: Is it from a… from a fan?
David Mendenhall: Is it a fan letter?
Kostadis Roussos: It's… you should read it all.
Wade: I'm a friend to two true justice.
David Mendenhall: I'm… I'm… I'm hoping it's a fan letter. I've never gotten a fan letter.
Kostadis Roussos: It is a fan letter in a very roundabout way.
David Mendenhall: Oh, well then I'll definitely want to read it.
Wade: Oh my god!
Wade: Mark Astor's back!
Gary Young: Wait, Housemargaster?
Wade: Yeah.
Gary Young: Oh my goodness.
David Mendenhall: All those guys….
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm.
Wade: Have a fan!
David Mendenhall: Everybody's evil.
David Mendenhall: Well, like I said, I wasn't sure that I fully trusted him. I did say that, just about 5 minutes.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. So, you did receive… I am being more cautious. I'm not wearing the pin. The pin is gone. Okay.
David Mendenhall: Lost in battle.
Kostadis Roussos: That's fine, I just want to make sure you did get the note, yes.
David Mendenhall: Can I cast identify on the note?
Kostadis Roussos: It's not magical.
Wade: Man, there's another pearl gone.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's what I… you read the rules, there's, like, I think there's a spell called Legend and Lore, I think that's the one you're looking for.
David Mendenhall: That's really high level, isn't it?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
David Mendenhall: Legends lore….
Gary Young: It says…
Gary Young: Level 5 spell.
David Mendenhall: That's a level 5 spell, yeah, it's pretty far away.
Wade: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: And… it's something famous. It's only for things that are famous.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's really for whatever the GM wants to be bothered to create lore for, so the GM doesn't get…
Kostadis Roussos: Hammered by players casting Legend Lore.
Gary Young: Every trinket.
Kostadis Roussos: Just so we're on the same page.
Kostadis Roussos: The real balance, the real game balance, yeah. Right, just to be clear, as a GM, yeah, you don't need to do spell components. No, no, but for that spell, oh yeah.
David Mendenhall: You're gonna have to.
David Mendenhall: How many pearls do you have? You don't have any pearls. Oh, wait, you have 6… I gave you 6 pearls? Why was I thinking?
Kostadis Roussos: Fix it.
Wade: Guy rolled for him.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, I thought you cached those pearls just the other day.
David Mendenhall: Nope, we didn't.
Wade: No, we hadn't… we got them in the… in the lighthouse, right?
Kostadis Roussos: I was just joking that usually, Gary, first thing they do, you go to a town and Gary converts everything.
David Mendenhall: Immediately.
Wade: Yeah, we can't do that with you.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, when we walked into town, like, can we sell this treasure? And I was like, no!
Wade: We can't do that with who crawdin in the mix, like, we gotta, like, I don't know, do a B.A. Baracas on him or something to sell our treasure.
Wade: Here, drink this milk, you know?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Some warm tea.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Morning… so you got the note in the morning, alright?
David Mendenhall: That was from the Harpers.
Gary Young: That, that was the only event during the rest cycle. Okay, got it.
David Mendenhall: That was the only… I think after hearing about the Harpers, And… Now getting this note… I think…
David Mendenhall: I think I am interested in connecting with them.
Kostadis Roussos: With who?
David Mendenhall: The Harpers.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: … do you declare that publicly?
David Mendenhall: I'm pregnant.
Wade: No, I think we're, ….
David Mendenhall: For the days of public declarations are over!
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, just….
Wade: We all have, like, an uncommon language we all speak, so we can have our discussions.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm assuming if you're not, like.
David Mendenhall: camp.
Kostadis Roussos: Shouting… if you're not shouting in town….
David Mendenhall: We're in our bedroom, right? We just woke up, and there.
Wade: Nope.
David Mendenhall: here.
Wade: We all share a bedroom?
Gary Young: My… my investigation was, you know, like, does it seem like there's some way that they got in, you know, like, scuff marks?
Wade: It just slid under the door, I assume.
Kostadis Roussos: Split under the door.
Wade: Oh, okay. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
David Mendenhall: … I guess we could ask… the, …
David Mendenhall: The Tavern Master, if there were any unusual visitors.
Gary Young: Last night?
Kostadis Roussos: ….
David Mendenhall: Anyone out of the ordinary come through?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you.
Wade: Just come upstairs and not stay?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, why do you ask?
David Mendenhall: I just thought I heard something last night.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, no, nothing, nothing. Then he turns to you, oh, but by the way, did you get the note?
Wade: Oh, it was….
Gary Young: Huh?
Wade: Spider-Man.
Kostadis Roussos: Where did the notes come from?
David Mendenhall: Kim.
Kostadis Roussos: It's from Neverwinter. I was told to give it to you. Oh, you were the middleman, okay.
David Mendenhall: Who, who gave it to you?
Kostadis Roussos: It came with the post.
David Mendenhall: -Oh.
Wade: Who would Neverwinter knows we're here? How are we on Neverwinter's radar?
David Mendenhall: No, because we took the jobs… we took the job in Neverwinter.
Wade: Oh, yeah….
David Mendenhall: I suppose. It came in the post. It came in the post. Okay.
Gary Young: Shadows? What, what, what, what, what, the… How many letters were there?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I was just given this one.
Gary Young: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you giving it to us right now?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he gave….
David Mendenhall: The le- it's the letter.
Kostadis Roussos: It's the letter he… I put it underneath your door.
David Mendenhall: He's the one who slid it under the door.
Gary Young: And you said it came from Neverwinter.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Ugh.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't… I don't ask, I don't ask where somebody's… somebody's… somebody's… somebody's notes come from. I'm a gentleman.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't sit there and pry and say, who is it from? What was the purpose of the letter? Why was it sent? I was presented with this, and I gave it.
David Mendenhall: Makes sense. It was a private letter, so thank you for delivering it. It was a private letter, I figured it… I just… I forgot to give it to you last night. Have a silver piece.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, thank you, thank you, thank you. Thank you, I forgot to give it to you last night, that's all.
David Mendenhall: Alright, what's next, folks?
Kostadis Roussos: Next is, we're out of time, so….
Gary Young: What Spring Woods?
Kostadis Roussos: woods?
David Mendenhall: I'm gonna say Soma had trouble sleeping with that hanging around. Soma wants to take on the Whispering Grove?
Wade: after Adabra's mention of it and all, yeah, I originally.
David Mendenhall: Well, you know, we're friends, I can back you up on that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Maybe that's where the carver is.
Wade: I have my doubts.
David Mendenhall: Me too.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: I don't think you're gonna come back with any money.
Wade: So you're gonna come back with a happier guide.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that is true. That is… a happy guide is a safer guide.
David Mendenhall: Well, the more of these organizations we can get on our side, probably the better for us.
Wade: It's gonna… we're gonna, you know….
David Mendenhall: Allies with all of them.
Wade: Until they, you know, find out that we're allies with their enemies.
David Mendenhall: They're not enemies!
Kostadis Roussos: I just want to be careful.
David Mendenhall: They have differences of opinion.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, and just to be clear, in my campaigns, because I can't be bothered to, factions have factions.
Kostadis Roussos: Welcome to.
Kostadis Roussos: not everybody within an organization agrees with everybody else. They have ambitions and goals and whatnot. Just keep that… just keep that in mind. They're not, you know….
David Mendenhall: Ser Kaelen is not every member of the Order of the Gauntlet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and doesn't necessarily agree with everybody in the Order of the Gauntlet, and you might meet other members of the Order of the Gauntlet who might have a very different perspective than.
Wade: Oh, you said factions have factions. I heard, like, actions have factions. I'm like, that made no sense.
Kostadis Roussos: factions.
Wade: Yes. They're not.
Wade: There's a schism every other day, I gotcha.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and the more… the more blinkered you are, the more likely, you know, the more pure… the more purist you are, the more…
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I figure the bigger you are, right, the bigger the org, so I always have to admit. Well, you know, it's kind of like, you know, the more purist you are, the more likely you are to have factions, so the Order of the Gauntlet, for example.
Kostadis Roussos: And the Emerald Enclave are more liable to factions than the Harpers.
Kostadis Roussos: and the Zhintarim were motivated… well, the Zentarim is very… they have factions because, well.
Kostadis Roussos: They're a bunch of cutthroats.
David Mendenhall: Well, they're all gonna stab each other in the back.
Wade: Yeah, they're Game of Thrones, the most unbelievable group of, you know….
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, they've got… their factions are, at least for rational reasons, the accumulation of power and wealth.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? I mean….
David Mendenhall: I see myself allying with the Zentara.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you know, the Lord's Alliance also has factions, because yes, we're all parts of the Lord's Alliance, but everybody's trying to conquer everybody else.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and they're all trying to grow their realms.
David Mendenhall: And there's always the seer in the background keeping the balance.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright then.
David Mendenhall: night.
Wade: Good night, hope you guys had fun.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Wade: Had a good one.